<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CompSoc Cookbook</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CompSoc Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 17:30:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate cupcakes</title>
      <link>/recipes/chocolate-cupcakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 17:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chocolate-cupcakes/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is adapted from a vegetarian cookbook, and it&amp;rsquo;s quickly become a favorite for its delicious frosting and fluffy base!
Prep time: 1 hour
Serves 12 cupcakes
Ingredients For the cupcake
 175g plain or all-purpose flour 2tsp cocoa powder 1.5tsp baking powder 140g sugar 25g ground almonds 2 large eggs 175g full-fat yogurt 2-3 drops vanilla extract 25g butter, melted 2tsp rapeseed oil  For the frosting
 25g dark chocolate, finely chopped 1tbsp dark chocolate, grated for decorating 25g butter, softened 50g icing (powdered) sugar 1tbsp cocoa powder 1tsp semi-skimmed milk 100g low-fat curd cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulgar Wheat with Pine Nuts, Carrot and Feta</title>
      <link>/recipes/bulgar_wheat_with_pine_nuts_carrot_and_feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/bulgar_wheat_with_pine_nuts_carrot_and_feta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g bulgur wheat 70g sultanas 500ml hot vegetable/chicken stock 2 medium carrots, coarsely grated 3 tbsp pine nuts 100g feta, crumbled (about half a packet) juice &amp;amp; zest 1/2 lemon 3 tbsp rapeseed/olive oil  Method  Put the bulgur and sultanas in a large bowl and pour over the hot stock. Cover with cling film and leave for 20-30 mins for the liquid to be absorbed. After the soaking, fluff the grains with a fork and leave to cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&lt;unnamed&gt;</title>
      <link>/recipes/pizza-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/pizza-base/</guid>
      <description>Fool-proof Pizza Base Your friends and family are going to ask you whether Gordon Ramsay assisted.
As seen on https://github.com/elenalape/pizza
Ingredients:  1 large cup/2 normal cups all-purpose flour 1/2 cup warm water 1 tsp dry yeast 0.75 tsp salt 1/2 tsp sugar 1 tbsp olive oil Optional: garlic powder  Method:  Add a small amount of warm (not hot, you&amp;rsquo;ll kill the yeast!) water into a mug and mix with yeast and sugar until both dissolve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate roll</title>
      <link>/recipes/chocolate-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chocolate-roll/</guid>
      <description>This no-bake roll with biscuits and cocoa is a Romanian family favorite dessert! Inspired by this recipe with a couple of modifications.
Serves an entire family
Ingredients  200g butter biscuits (you can add more to taste - Leibniz type biscuits should work best) 50g cocoa powder 130g butter 100ml milk 125g sugar (either brown or white) 50g dark chocolate (at least 50% cocoa) rum essence (not necessary but it makes the taste much better - any Polish store should have it) vanilla sugar powdered sugar extra filling: nuts, almonds, raisins, cranberries, candied fruit, finely chopped Turkish delight, coconut flakes, or several of these!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Pot Spaghetti &amp; Meat Sauce</title>
      <link>/recipes/instant-pot-spaghetti-meat-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/instant-pot-spaghetti-meat-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Super duper easy recipe for spaghetti &amp;amp; meat sauce that you can do right in an instant pot.
Serves 4
Ingredients  8 oz dry pasta (spaghetti works best) 1 tbsp olive oil 500g ground beef Small onion 475ml water 24oz tomato sauce (1 jar, or equiv. homemade) Garlic powder Onion powder Kosher salt Pepper Red pepper flakes Grated parmesan (for serving)  Method  Set your instant pot to Sauté, and once it&amp;rsquo;s hot add the olive oil and minced onion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuffed peppers with mushrooms</title>
      <link>/recipes/stuffed-peppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/stuffed-peppers/</guid>
      <description>This vegan recipe is sure to impress your guests and makes for a lovely main course!
Adapted from this recipe with slight alterations - check it out if you need visuals.
Serves 8-11
Ingredients  11 peppers (I tend to use red or yellow) 3 brown onions, finely chopped 2 carrots, coarsely grated 300g Champignon mushrooms (any of the smaller mushrooms varieties should do), washed and finely chopped 200g rice (risotto or generally white rice) 1 bunch of fresh dill, finely chopped 1 can chopped tomatoes 1 tbsp dry thyme 60ml oil 1 tsp salt 1 tsp pepper 2 vegetable stock cubes  Method  Add oil to the pan along with the onions and the carrots, fry for 7-8 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textbook (Wikipedia inspired) Piña Colada</title>
      <link>/recipes/wikipedia_pina_colada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/wikipedia_pina_colada/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 part white rum 1 part (Alpro) coconut drink 3 parts pineapple juice Ice  Method  Add ice to shaker Pour in all liquids Shake for an arbitrary amount of time Profit!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark &amp; Dirty Mojito</title>
      <link>/recipes/dark_and_dirty_mojito/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/dark_and_dirty_mojito/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 parts spiced rum 1 part ginger beer 2 part soda 2 part sugar water 1 part lime juice 5-10 mint leaves Ice  Method  Add ice and mint to the glass and bruise mint Add all liquids except lime juice and stir Squeeze in lime juice, add the lime and stir Pack with ice if desired and serve  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Spanish&#34; Eggs</title>
      <link>/recipes/spanish-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/spanish-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Serves 3
Ingredients  1/2 ring of chorizo, chopped into small semi/quarter circles 1 red onion, sliced in half and chopped into thin semicircles 1 red or yellow pepper, deseeded and chopped into 1in chunks 2-3 eggs per person 2 garlic cloves, finely chopped 1.5 tsp chilli flakes (adjust to preference)  Method  Heat some oil in a pan over a medium heat. Add the chorizo and cook until they have released their oil and are becoming cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon, Potato And Split Pea Soup</title>
      <link>/recipes/bacon-potato-and-split-pea-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/bacon-potato-and-split-pea-soup/</guid>
      <description>Serves 6
Ingredients  6 rashers of bacon, cut into 1in strips 1 onion, diced 2 cloves of garlic, minced 450g yellow split peas 1.5L chicken stock 1 bay leaf 700g potatoes (usually 1/4 of a bag)  Method  Fry the bacon in a large pot over a medium heat. Once the bacon has browned, add the chopped onion and garlic to the pot and fry for another 5 minutes until the onions are translucent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Sausage With Sweet Potato And Fennel</title>
      <link>/recipes/baked-sausage-with-sweet-potato-and-fennel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/baked-sausage-with-sweet-potato-and-fennel/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  500g sweet potatoes (approx. 2 large ones), peeled 1 healthy-sized fennel bulb 3 garlic cloves, peeled and sliced 1 tsp celery seeds 1 tbsp dark brown sugar 3 tbsp olive oil 8 solid, good-quality sausages 8 smoked back bacon rashers 1 tbsp plain flour 100ml apple juice 50ml dry white wine (rough measurement) 2 tbsp balsamic vinegar 1 or 2 sprigs of thyme or fennel fronds if you can find them Salt and pepper  Method  Preheat the oven to 200C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brazilian Coconut Chicken</title>
      <link>/recipes/brazilian-coconut-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/brazilian-coconut-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground cayenne pepper 1 tsp ground turmeric 1 tsp ground coriander 4 chicken breasts, chopped into cubes 1 onion, chopped 1 tbsp minced fresh ginger 2 green chillies, seeded and chopped 2 cloves garlic, minced 3 tomatoes, seeded and chopped 1 (400ml) tin light coconut milk  Method  In a mixing bowl, combine the spices and place the chicken in, seasoning with salt and pepper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken and Lentil Dahl</title>
      <link>/recipes/chicken-and-lentil-dahl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chicken-and-lentil-dahl/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  215g red lentils 500g chicken breasts, cut in half 3/4 teaspoon salt, or to taste 1/2 teaspoon turmeric 2 tablespoons grated fresh ginger 1 teaspoon ground ginger 3 teaspoons cumin seeds 5 black cardamom pods or 10 green cardamom pods, lightly crushed 2 tablespoons olive oil 1 small onion, thinly sliced 6 garlic cloves, finely chopped 2-6 green chillies, chopped (based on preference)  Method  Place the lentils, chicken, salt, turmeric, fresh ginger, ground ginger, 2 teaspoons of the cumin seeds and the cardamom pods in a deep saucepan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Satay</title>
      <link>/recipes/chicken-satay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chicken-satay/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  3 tbsp crunchy peanut butter 3 tbsp sweet chilli sauce 2 tbsp soy sauce 300g noodles thumb-sized bit of fresh ginger peeled and chopped 1tbsp oil 300g stir fry veg (mange tout, sugar snap peas, tenderstem broccoli, bean sprouts etc.) handful of cooked chicken handful basil 25g roasted peanuts (optional)  Method  Mix PB, chilli sauce, soy sauce and 100ml boiling water in a bowl to make the paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea Curry</title>
      <link>/recipes/chickpea-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chickpea-curry/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  1 tbsp oil 1 onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, thinly sliced 1 green pepper, cored, deseeded and chopped 150g red lentils, rinsed 2 tsp garam masala 1 tsp cumin seeds 1/2 tsp hot chilli powder 1 tsp ground coriander 2 tbsp tomato purée 700ml hot vegetable stock 400g tin chickpeas, drained 2 tbsp chopped coriander, to garnish salt and freshly ground black pepper  Method  Heat the oil in a heavy-based saucepan over a medium heat, add the onion, garlic and green pepper and fry gently for 10-12 minutes or until softened and beginning to colour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea, spinach and egg curry</title>
      <link>/recipes/chickpea_spinach_and_egg_curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chickpea_spinach_and_egg_curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 eggs 2 tsp cumin seeds 1 tsp black mustard seeds 2 tbsp medium curry powder 1 tsp garlic granules 1 tsp ground ginger 400g tin chopped tomatoes 400g tin chickpeas, drained &amp;amp; rinsed 1 tbsp lemon juice 100ml boiling water 180g baby spinach leaves Fresh coriander, to garnish  Method  Boil the eggs for 6-8 minutes. Shock in an ice bath once done to make peeling easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo and Pearl Barley Risotto</title>
      <link>/recipes/chorizo-and-pearl-barley-risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chorizo-and-pearl-barley-risotto/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  Chorizo ring, sliced into coins 1 onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 tsp smoked paprika 300g pearl barley 400g can of chopped tomatoes 1L hot chicken stock 2 stalks of rosemary, leaves chopped and stalks removed  Method  Heat a pan over a medium heat and fry chorizo for about 5 minutes until golden and have released its oil. Remove with a slotted spoon and set aside, covering with tin foil to keep warm (and stop you eating all of them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo Linguine</title>
      <link>/recipes/chorizo_linguine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/chorizo_linguine/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 people’s worth linguine, ~120g? 1/3 ring of chorizo, cut into thick quarter moons Juice of half a large lemon Handful fresh parsley, around 6 stems, plucked and finely chopped 2 tbsp capers, drained ~60g grated Parmesan/gran padano  Method  Bring a pot of heavily salted water to the boil and add the pasta, cooking until al-dente (roughly 8 minutes) Meanwhile in a large frying pan, fry the chorizo in a small bit of olive oil until it gives up its oil and becomes crispy Lower the heat and add the capers and fry for a minute, stirring frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courgette &amp; Mint soup</title>
      <link>/recipes/courgette-and-mint-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/courgette-and-mint-soup/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  knob of butter 1 onion, chopped 1kg courgettes, roughly chopped 1/2 tsp dried mint 1.3L vegetable stock 3-4 sprigs fresh mint Soured cream/yoghurt/single cream, to serve  Method  Heat butter in a large saucepan, add the onion and cooky gently until soft. Add the courgettes and dried mint, and stir well to mix with the onion. Cover and cook over a gentle heat for about 10 mins until the courgettes are softened but not charred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gorgonzola risotto with sun dried tomatoes</title>
      <link>/recipes/gorgonzola_risotto_with_sun_dried_tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/gorgonzola_risotto_with_sun_dried_tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1.2L stock (chicken or veg) 240ml dry white wine (e.g. Pinot Grigio) 300g risotto rice 280g jar of sun dried tomatoes in oil, chopped (slow roasted tomatoes also work) 1 onion, finely chopped 3 cloves garlic, minced 250g Gorgonzola, chopped into small pieces 25g butter Fresh basil for dressing  Method  Heat the stock in a saucepan over a low heat so it’s simmering gently Chop up the onion and the tomatoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harissa Chicken Traybake</title>
      <link>/recipes/harissa-chicken-traybake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/harissa-chicken-traybake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 tbsp harissa 3 tbsp low-fat natural yogurt 4 skinless chicken breasts, slashed 1 small butternut squash, peeled, deseeded and cut into wedges 2 red onions, cut into wedges  (Other vegetables also work, such as shallots, sweet potato(!), peppers, etc)
Method  Heat oven to 200C/180C fan. Mix 2 tbsp of harissa with the yogurt and rub all over the chicken breasts and set aside to marinate while you start the veg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb Koftas</title>
      <link>/recipes/lamb-koftas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/lamb-koftas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g lamb mince 2 tsp ground cumin Chilli flakes, to taste 2 tbsp chopped parsley leaves 2 tbsp chopped mint leaves Salt Pepper  Method  Mix together all ingredients until well blended. Roll the lamb mixture into pieces the size of golf balls and flatten them into patties about 1 cm thick. Place on a plate drizzled with a little olive oil, and drizzle the tops of the patties with more oil, ready for cooking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pierogi</title>
      <link>/recipes/pierogi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/pierogi/</guid>
      <description>Dough Ingredients  0.5kg plain flour 1 large eggs 1 glass of lukewarm water 1 tbsp of oil Pinch of salt  Method To make the dough:
 Mix flour and salt in a bowl/on a kneading board (as for pasta). Make a well in the centre and add the eggs and oil into it. Mix together, slowly adding water, until it forms a smooth and non-sticky dough. Leave to rest, covered by a clean tea towel or cling film, for 30mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork &amp; Pistachio Meatloaf</title>
      <link>/recipes/pork-and-pistachio-meatloaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/pork-and-pistachio-meatloaf/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100g white breadcrumbs 150g pistachio nuts, roughly chopped 1kg pork mince 50g pickled gherkins, chopped into pieces 1 tbsp English mustard 3 garlic cloves, peeled and crushed 2 medium free range eggs, beaten Salt and pepper  Method  Preheat the oven to 180C fan. Line the base of a 900g non-stick loaf tin with grease proof paper. Combine all the ingredients in a large bowl. Get your hands involved to really squidge everything together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Casserole</title>
      <link>/recipes/sausage-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/sausage-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  12 sausages 6 rashers rindless streaky bacon, cut into 2.5cm/1in lengths 2 medium onions, thinly sliced 2 garlic cloves, crushed 1 tsp hot chilli powder or smoked paprika 400g tin chopped tomatoes 300ml chicken stock 2 tbsp tomato purée 1 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 tbsp dark brown muscovado sugar 1 tsp dried mixed herbs 2 bay leaves 3–4 sprigs of fresh thyme 100ml red or white wine (optional, but encouraged) 400g tin butter beans or mixed beans salt and freshly ground black pepper  Method  Heat a tablespoon of the oil in a large non-stick frying pan and fry the sausages gently for 10 minutes, turning every now and then until nicely browned all over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage, Apple and Leek Pie</title>
      <link>/recipes/sausage-apple-and-leek-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/sausage-apple-and-leek-pie/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  8 sausages 1 apple, peeled and sliced into small bits 3 leeks, sliced (depending on size) 1 tbsp plain flour 1 tbsp grainy mustard 300ml stock 375g ready-rolled shortcut pastry 1 egg, beaten  Method  Preheat oven to 200C/Fan 180C. Fry sausages in large frying pan until brown on all sides. Remove from the frying pan and set to one side. Fry the leeks for 8-10 minutes until softened, then add the apple and fry for 1 minute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Cooker Bánh Mì</title>
      <link>/recipes/slow-cooker-banh-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/slow-cooker-banh-mi/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  2kg pork shoulder 2 jalapeño, diced 2 2in piece of ginger, sliced thin 8 cloves garlic, minced 250ml soy sauce 120ml white wine/cider vinegar 220g brown sugar  Method  Season the pork shoulder with salt and pepper. In the slow cooker, stir together the jalapeño, ginger, garlic, soy sauce, vinegar and brown sugar. Nestle the pork in the liquid. Cover and cook on low for 8 hours or high for 4-5hrs  To serve: Serve in warmed baguettes with mayonnaise, sriracha and pickled carrots and pickled red cabbage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Cooker Honey Sriracha Chicken</title>
      <link>/recipes/slow-cooker-honey-sriracha-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/slow-cooker-honey-sriracha-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  6 chicken thighs, bone-in &amp;amp; skin on 4 tbsp ketchup (spicy, Polish ketchup recommended) 4 tbsp soy sauce 4 tbsp honey 1 lime, juiced 2 tbsp Sriracha 3 cloves garlic, minced  Method  Heat oil in large frying pan over high heat. Add chicken and sear until golden brown on both sides, 2-3 minutes on each side. Transfer chicken to slow cooker. In a bowl, combine ketchup, soy sauce, honey, lime juice, sriracha and garlic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow-Roasted Pork Belly with Fennel</title>
      <link>/recipes/slow_roasted_pork_belly_with_fennel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/slow_roasted_pork_belly_with_fennel/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg pork belly 1 fennel bulb, trimmed and roughly sliced 4 fresh bay leaves 3 garlic cloves, peeled and bashed 1 tsp cardamom pods, bashed 4 star anise 1 tbsp fennel seeds 325ml white wine 500-750ml chicken stock 1 tbsp wholegrain mustard  Method  Preheat the oven to 180C/fan 160C Score the pork belly skin diagonally in a diamond pattern at 1.5cm intervals. Season generously with salt and pepper rubbing it well into the skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steak Pie</title>
      <link>/recipes/steak-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/steak-pie/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  900g stewing/braising steak, cut into cubes 25g plain flour, seasoned with salt and pepper 1 tbsp olive oil 2 onions, sliced 1 tbsp chopped fresh parsley 1 tbsp chopped fresh thyme 850ml / 1.5 pints hot beef stock 225g ready-rolled shortcrust pastry 1 egg, beaten  Method  Roll the cubed steak in the seasoned flour until well coated. Heat the oil in a large heavy-bottomed frying bowl and fry the meat, stirring frequently, until browned on all sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Eggs</title>
      <link>/recipes/thai-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/thai-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tbsp Thai green curry paste 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp fish sauce 1 tsp oyster sauce (optional) 2-3 eggs per person 1 green peppers, deseeded and chopped into 1in chunks 2 handfuls spinach per person 1/2 lime/lemon per person (either citrus works)  Method  Heat some oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add the curry paste to the pan and fry for 1-2 minutes until it releases its fragrance, stirring frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Green Curry</title>
      <link>/recipes/best-thai-green-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/best-thai-green-curry/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  2 tbsp Thai green curry paste (adjust for spice tolerance) 1 tbsp soft dark brown sugar 1-2 thick stalks lemongrass, fat ends bashed with a rolling pin (optional) 750g chicken, cut into chunks 6-8 kaffir lime leaves, torn into pieces 400ml coconut milk (have a spare in case you need to take the spice out) Good shake of Thai fish sauce or light soy sauce Small handful of coriander, roughly chopped 1/2 - 1 lime, juice only  Method  Heat the oil in a wok or large frying pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Eggs / Shakshuka</title>
      <link>/recipes/turkish-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/turkish-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4
Ingredients  2 small onion 4 eggs 1 tin chopped tomatoes 1 red pepper, deseeded and sliced 1-2 red chillies, deseeded and sliced 1-2 tsp caster sugar 2 sprigs thyme 1.5 tsp ground cumin 1 tbsp parsley, roughly chopped 2 garlic cloves, crushed 6 tbsp thick, creamy yogurt  Method  Heat the oil in a heavy-based frying pan. Stir in the onions, pepper and chillies. Cook until they begin to soften.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipes</title>
      <link>/recipes/view-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/view-all/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
