<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0-easy on CompSoc Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/difficulties/0-easy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 0-easy on CompSoc Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 05:17:02 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/difficulties/0-easy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pink Lady</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/pink-lady/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 05:17:02 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/pink-lady/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of this old cocktail shaker I found in a charity shop
Ingredients  3-4 Ice Cubes (Crushed) 1 Tsp Grenadine 1 Measure Gin 1 Egg White A Sliver of Orange Peel (Optional)  Method  Add ice to shaker Pour in all liquids &amp;amp; egg whites Shake until most of the ice has melted Add the orange peel in the glass for a bit of pizzaz (pizzaz optional) Crunk  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Spanish&#34; Eggs</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/spanish-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/spanish-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 ring of chorizo, chopped into small semi/quarter circles 1 red onion, sliced in half and chopped into thin semicircles 1 red or yellow pepper, deseeded and chopped into 1in chunks 2-3 eggs per person 2 garlic cloves, finely chopped 1.5 tsp chilli flakes (adjust to preference)  Method  Heat some oil in a pan over a medium heat. Add the chorizo and cook until they have released their oil and are becoming cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Satay</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chicken-satay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chicken-satay/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 tbsp crunchy peanut butter 3 tbsp sweet chilli sauce 2 tbsp soy sauce 300g noodles thumb-sized bit of fresh ginger peeled and chopped 1tbsp oil 300g stir fry veg (mange tout, sugar snap peas, tenderstem broccoli, bean sprouts etc.) handful of cooked chicken handful basil 25g roasted peanuts (optional)  Method  Mix PB, chilli sauce, soy sauce and 100ml boiling water in a bowl to make the paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fool-proof Pizza Base</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/pizza-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/pizza-base/</guid>
      <description>Your friends and family are going to ask you whether Gordon Ramsay assisted.
As seen on https://github.com/elenalape/pizza Ingredients:  1 large cup/2 normal cups all-purpose flour 1/2 cup warm water 1 tsp dry yeast 0.75 tsp salt 1/2 tsp sugar 1 tbsp olive oil Optional: garlic powder  Method:  Add a small amount of warm (not hot, you&amp;rsquo;ll kill the yeast!) water into a mug and mix with yeast and sugar until both dissolve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Pot Spaghetti &amp; Meat Sauce</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/instant-pot-spaghetti-meat-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/instant-pot-spaghetti-meat-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Super duper easy recipe for spaghetti &amp;amp; meat sauce that you can do right in an instant pot.
Ingredients  8 oz dry pasta (spaghetti works best) 1 tbsp olive oil 500g ground beef Small onion 475ml water 24oz tomato sauce (1 jar, or equiv. homemade) Garlic powder Onion powder Kosher salt Pepper Red pepper flakes Grated parmesan (for serving)  Method  Set your instant pot to Sauté, and once it&amp;rsquo;s hot add the olive oil and minced onion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Casserole</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/sausage-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/sausage-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  12 sausages 6 rashers rindless streaky bacon, cut into 2.5cm/1in lengths 2 medium onions, thinly sliced 2 garlic cloves, crushed 1 tsp hot chilli powder or smoked paprika 400g tin chopped tomatoes 300ml chicken stock 2 tbsp tomato purée 1 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 tbsp dark brown muscovado sugar 1 tsp dried mixed herbs 2 bay leaves 3–4 sprigs of fresh thyme 100ml red or white wine (optional, but encouraged) 400g tin butter beans or mixed beans salt and freshly ground black pepper  Method  Heat a tablespoon of the oil in a large non-stick frying pan and fry the sausages gently for 10 minutes, turning every now and then until nicely browned all over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage, Apple and Leek Pie</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/sausage-apple-and-leek-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/sausage-apple-and-leek-pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 sausages 1 apple, peeled and sliced into small bits 3 leeks, sliced (depending on size) 1 tbsp plain flour 1 tbsp grainy mustard 300ml stock 375g ready-rolled shortcut pastry 1 egg, beaten  Method  Preheat oven to 200C/Fan 180C. Fry sausages in large frying pan until brown on all sides. Remove from the frying pan and set to one side. Fry the leeks for 8-10 minutes until softened, then add the apple and fry for 1 minute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Cooker Bánh Mì</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/slow-cooker-banh-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/slow-cooker-banh-mi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2kg pork shoulder 2 jalapeño, diced 2 2in piece of ginger, sliced thin 8 cloves garlic, minced 250ml soy sauce 120ml white wine/cider vinegar 220g brown sugar  Method  Season the pork shoulder with salt and pepper. In the slow cooker, stir together the jalapeño, ginger, garlic, soy sauce, vinegar and brown sugar. Nestle the pork in the liquid. Cover and cook on low for 8 hours or high for 4-5hrs  To serve: Serve in warmed baguettes with mayonnaise, sriracha and pickled carrots and pickled red cabbage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Cooker Honey Sriracha Chicken</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/slow-cooker-honey-sriracha-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/slow-cooker-honey-sriracha-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  6 chicken thighs, bone-in &amp;amp; skin on 4 tbsp ketchup (spicy, Polish ketchup recommended) 4 tbsp soy sauce 4 tbsp honey 1 lime, juiced 2 tbsp Sriracha 3 cloves garlic, minced  Method  Heat oil in large frying pan over high heat. Add chicken and sear until golden brown on both sides, 2-3 minutes on each side. Transfer chicken to slow cooker. In a bowl, combine ketchup, soy sauce, honey, lime juice, sriracha and garlic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Eggs / Shakshuka</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/turkish-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/turkish-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 small onion 4 eggs 1 tin chopped tomatoes 1 red pepper, deseeded and sliced 1-2 red chillies, deseeded and sliced 1-2 tsp caster sugar 2 sprigs thyme 1.5 tsp ground cumin 1 tbsp parsley, roughly chopped 2 garlic cloves, crushed 6 tbsp thick, creamy yogurt  Method  Heat the oil in a heavy-based frying pan. Stir in the onions, pepper and chillies. Cook until they begin to soften.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulgar Wheat with Pine Nuts, Carrot and Feta</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/bulgar_wheat_with_pine_nuts_carrot_and_feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/bulgar_wheat_with_pine_nuts_carrot_and_feta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g bulgur wheat 70g sultanas 500ml hot vegetable/chicken stock 2 medium carrots, coarsely grated 3 tbsp pine nuts 100g feta, crumbled (about half a packet) juice &amp;amp; zest 1/2 lemon 3 tbsp rapeseed/olive oil  Method  Put the bulgur and sultanas in a large bowl and pour over the hot stock. Cover with cling film and leave for 20-30 mins for the liquid to be absorbed. After the soaking, fluff the grains with a fork and leave to cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textbook (Wikipedia inspired) Piña Colada</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/wikipedia_pina_colada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/wikipedia_pina_colada/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 part white rum 1 part (Alpro) coconut drink 3 parts pineapple juice Ice  Method  Add ice to shaker Pour in all liquids Shake for an arbitrary amount of time Profit!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark &amp; Dirty Mojito</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/dark_and_dirty_mojito/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/dark_and_dirty_mojito/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 parts spiced rum 1 part ginger beer 2 part soda 2 part sugar water 1 part lime juice 5-10 mint leaves Ice  Method  Add ice and mint to the glass and bruise mint Add all liquids except lime juice and stir Squeeze in lime juice, add the lime and stir Pack with ice if desired and serve  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea, spinach and egg curry</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chickpea_spinach_and_egg_curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chickpea_spinach_and_egg_curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 eggs 2 tsp cumin seeds 1 tsp black mustard seeds 2 tbsp medium curry powder 1 tsp garlic granules 1 tsp ground ginger 400g tin chopped tomatoes 400g tin chickpeas, drained &amp;amp; rinsed 1 tbsp lemon juice 100ml boiling water 180g baby spinach leaves Fresh coriander, to garnish  Method  Boil the eggs for 6-8 minutes. Shock in an ice bath once done to make peeling easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo Linguine</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chorizo_linguine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chorizo_linguine/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 people’s worth linguine, ~120g? 1/3 ring of chorizo, cut into thick quarter moons Juice of half a large lemon Handful fresh parsley, around 6 stems, plucked and finely chopped 2 tbsp capers, drained ~60g grated Parmesan/gran padano  Method  Bring a pot of heavily salted water to the boil and add the pasta, cooking until al-dente (roughly 8 minutes) Meanwhile in a large frying pan, fry the chorizo in a small bit of olive oil until it gives up its oil and becomes crispy Lower the heat and add the capers and fry for a minute, stirring frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
