<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1-medium on CompSoc Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/difficulties/1-medium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1-medium on CompSoc Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/difficulties/1-medium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baked Sausage With Sweet Potato And Fennel</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/baked-sausage-with-sweet-potato-and-fennel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/baked-sausage-with-sweet-potato-and-fennel/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 500g sweet potatoes (approx. 2 large ones), peeled 1 healthy-sized fennel bulb 3 garlic cloves, peeled and sliced 1 tsp celery seeds 1 tbsp dark brown sugar 3 tbsp olive oil 8 solid, good-quality sausages 8 smoked back bacon rashers 1 tbsp plain flour 100ml apple juice 50ml dry white wine (rough measurement) 2 tbsp balsamic vinegar 1 or 2 sprigs of thyme or fennel fronds if you can find them Salt and pepper Method Preheat the oven to 200C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate cupcakes</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chocolate-cupcakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chocolate-cupcakes/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is adapted from a vegetarian cookbook, and it&amp;rsquo;s quickly become a favorite for its delicious frosting and fluffy base!
Ingredients For the cupcake
175g plain or all-purpose flour 2tsp cocoa powder 1.5tsp baking powder 140g sugar 25g ground almonds 2 large eggs 175g full-fat yogurt 2-3 drops vanilla extract 25g butter, melted 2tsp rapeseed oil For the frosting
25g dark chocolate, finely chopped 1tbsp dark chocolate, grated for decorating 25g butter, softened 50g icing (powdered) sugar 1tbsp cocoa powder 1tsp semi-skimmed milk 100g low-fat curd cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate roll</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chocolate-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chocolate-roll/</guid>
      <description>This no-bake roll with biscuits and cocoa is a Romanian family favorite dessert! Inspired by this recipe with a couple of modifications.
Ingredients 200g butter biscuits (you can add more to taste - Leibniz type biscuits should work best) 50g cocoa powder 130g butter 100ml milk 125g sugar (either brown or white) 50g dark chocolate (at least 50% cocoa) rum essence (not necessary but it makes the taste much better - any Polish store should have it) vanilla sugar powdered sugar extra filling: nuts, almonds, raisins, cranberries, candied fruit, finely chopped Turkish delight, coconut flakes, or several of these!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courgette &amp; Mint soup</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/courgette-and-mint-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/courgette-and-mint-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients knob of butter 1 onion, chopped 1kg courgettes, roughly chopped 1/2 tsp dried mint 1.3L vegetable stock 3-4 sprigs fresh mint Soured cream/yoghurt/single cream, to serve Method Heat butter in a large saucepan, add the onion and cooky gently until soft. Add the courgettes and dried mint, and stir well to mix with the onion. Cover and cook over a gentle heat for about 10 mins until the courgettes are softened but not charred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gorgonzola risotto with sun dried tomatoes</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/gorgonzola_risotto_with_sun_dried_tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/gorgonzola_risotto_with_sun_dried_tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1.2L stock (chicken or veg) 240ml dry white wine (e.g. Pinot Grigio) 300g risotto rice 280g jar of sun dried tomatoes in oil, chopped (slow roasted tomatoes also work) 1 onion, finely chopped 3 cloves garlic, minced 250g Gorgonzola, chopped into small pieces 25g butter Fresh basil for dressing Method Heat the stock in a saucepan over a low heat so it’s simmering gently Chop up the onion and the tomatoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harissa Chicken Traybake</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/harissa-chicken-traybake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/harissa-chicken-traybake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 3 tbsp harissa 3 tbsp low-fat natural yogurt 4 skinless chicken breasts, slashed 1 small butternut squash, peeled, deseeded and cut into wedges 2 red onions, cut into wedges (Other vegetables also work, such as shallots, sweet potato(!), peppers, etc)
Method Heat oven to 200C/180C fan. Mix 2 tbsp of harissa with the yogurt and rub all over the chicken breasts and set aside to marinate while you start the veg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork &amp; Pistachio Meatloaf</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/pork-and-pistachio-meatloaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/pork-and-pistachio-meatloaf/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 100g white breadcrumbs 150g pistachio nuts, roughly chopped 1kg pork mince 50g pickled gherkins, chopped into pieces 1 tbsp English mustard 3 garlic cloves, peeled and crushed 2 medium free range eggs, beaten Salt and pepper Method Preheat the oven to 180C fan. Line the base of a 900g non-stick loaf tin with grease proof paper. Combine all the ingredients in a large bowl. Get your hands involved to really squidge everything together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow-Roasted Pork Belly with Fennel</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/slow_roasted_pork_belly_with_fennel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/slow_roasted_pork_belly_with_fennel/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1kg pork belly 1 fennel bulb, trimmed and roughly sliced 4 fresh bay leaves 3 garlic cloves, peeled and bashed 1 tsp cardamom pods, bashed 4 star anise 1 tbsp fennel seeds 325ml white wine 500-750ml chicken stock 1 tbsp wholegrain mustard Method Preheat the oven to 180C/fan 160C Score the pork belly skin diagonally in a diamond pattern at 1.5cm intervals. Season generously with salt and pepper rubbing it well into the skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steak Pie</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/steak-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/steak-pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 900g stewing/braising steak, cut into cubes 25g plain flour, seasoned with salt and pepper 1 tbsp olive oil 2 onions, sliced 1 tbsp chopped fresh parsley 1 tbsp chopped fresh thyme 850ml / 1.5 pints hot beef stock 225g ready-rolled shortcrust pastry 1 egg, beaten Method Roll the cubed steak in the seasoned flour until well coated. Heat the oil in a large heavy-bottomed frying bowl and fry the meat, stirring frequently, until browned on all sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Eggs</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/thai-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/thai-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 tbsp Thai green curry paste 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp fish sauce 1 tsp oyster sauce (optional) 2-3 eggs per person 1 green peppers, deseeded and chopped into 1in chunks 2 handfuls spinach per person 1/2 lime/lemon per person (either citrus works) Method Heat some oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add the curry paste to the pan and fry for 1-2 minutes until it releases its fragrance, stirring frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Green Curry</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/best-thai-green-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/best-thai-green-curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 tbsp Thai green curry paste (adjust for spice tolerance) 1 tbsp soft dark brown sugar 1-2 thick stalks lemongrass, fat ends bashed with a rolling pin (optional) 750g chicken, cut into chunks 6-8 kaffir lime leaves, torn into pieces 400ml coconut milk (have a spare in case you need to take the spice out) Good shake of Thai fish sauce or light soy sauce Small handful of coriander, roughly chopped 1/2 - 1 lime, juice only Method Heat the oil in a wok or large frying pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon, Potato And Split Pea Soup</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/bacon-potato-and-split-pea-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/bacon-potato-and-split-pea-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 6 rashers of bacon, cut into 1in strips 1 onion, diced 2 cloves of garlic, minced 450g yellow split peas 1.5L chicken stock 1 bay leaf 700g potatoes (usually 1/4 of a bag) Method Fry the bacon in a large pot over a medium heat. Once the bacon has browned, add the chopped onion and garlic to the pot and fry for another 5 minutes until the onions are translucent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brazilian Coconut Chicken</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/brazilian-coconut-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/brazilian-coconut-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground cayenne pepper 1 tsp ground turmeric 1 tsp ground coriander 4 chicken breasts, chopped into cubes 1 onion, chopped 1 tbsp minced fresh ginger 2 green chillies, seeded and chopped 2 cloves garlic, minced 3 tomatoes, seeded and chopped 1 (400ml) tin light coconut milk Method In a mixing bowl, combine the spices and place the chicken in, seasoning with salt and pepper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken and Lentil Dahl</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chicken-and-lentil-dahl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chicken-and-lentil-dahl/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 215g red lentils 500g chicken breasts, cut in half 3/4 teaspoon salt, or to taste 1/2 teaspoon turmeric 2 tablespoons grated fresh ginger 1 teaspoon ground ginger 3 teaspoons cumin seeds 5 black cardamom pods or 10 green cardamom pods, lightly crushed 2 tablespoons olive oil 1 small onion, thinly sliced 6 garlic cloves, finely chopped 2-6 green chillies, chopped (based on preference) Method Place the lentils, chicken, salt, turmeric, fresh ginger, ground ginger, 2 teaspoons of the cumin seeds and the cardamom pods in a deep saucepan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea Curry</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chickpea-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chickpea-curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 tbsp oil 1 onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, thinly sliced 1 green pepper, cored, deseeded and chopped 150g red lentils, rinsed 2 tsp garam masala 1 tsp cumin seeds 1/2 tsp hot chilli powder 1 tsp ground coriander 2 tbsp tomato purée 700ml hot vegetable stock 400g tin chickpeas, drained 2 tbsp chopped coriander, to garnish salt and freshly ground black pepper Method Heat the oil in a heavy-based saucepan over a medium heat, add the onion, garlic and green pepper and fry gently for 10-12 minutes or until softened and beginning to colour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo and Pearl Barley Risotto</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chorizo-and-pearl-barley-risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/chorizo-and-pearl-barley-risotto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Chorizo ring, sliced into coins 1 onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 tsp smoked paprika 300g pearl barley 400g can of chopped tomatoes 1L hot chicken stock 2 stalks of rosemary, leaves chopped and stalks removed Method Heat a pan over a medium heat and fry chorizo for about 5 minutes until golden and have released its oil. Remove with a slotted spoon and set aside, covering with tin foil to keep warm (and stop you eating all of them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuffed peppers with mushrooms</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/stuffed-peppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 23:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/stuffed-peppers/</guid>
      <description>This vegan recipe is sure to impress your guests and makes for a lovely main course!
Adapted from this recipe with slight alterations - check it out if you need visuals.
Ingredients 11 peppers (I tend to use red or yellow) 3 brown onions, finely chopped 2 carrots, coarsely grated 300g Champignon mushrooms (any of the smaller mushrooms varieties should do), washed and finely chopped 200g rice (risotto or generally white rice) 1 bunch of fresh dill, finely chopped 1 can chopped tomatoes 1 tbsp dry thyme 60ml oil 1 tsp salt 1 tsp pepper 2 vegetable stock cubes Method Add oil to the pan along with the onions and the carrots, fry for 7-8 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb Koftas</title>
      <link>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/lamb-koftas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cookbook.comp-soc.com/recipes/lamb-koftas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 500g lamb mince 2 tsp ground cumin Chilli flakes, to taste 2 tbsp chopped parsley leaves 2 tbsp chopped mint leaves Salt Pepper Method Mix together all ingredients until well blended. Roll the lamb mixture into pieces the size of golf balls and flatten them into patties about 1 cm thick. Place on a plate drizzled with a little olive oil, and drizzle the tops of the patties with more oil, ready for cooking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
